# Jacquelyn Schmidt

## SUMMARY

I am a 5th year PhD candidate at the University of Michigan focused on developing sensor-based control systems and machine learning/AI methods to address challenges in urban stormwater infrastructure. I have 8 years of technical research experience, including 3 years working closely with water utilities and NGOs. Strong in analyzing multi-system problems, communicating complex ideas to diverse audiences, as well as overcoming technical and operational challenges, I am looking to apply these skills in my next opportunity.

## **EXPERIENCE**

# DIGITAL WATER LAB @ UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA

Aug 2019 - present

Graduate Research Assistant, University of Michigan

- Developed full-stack technologies for urban stormwater management (IoT sensors, machine learning/AI, data analysis pipelines, web applications, data visualization).
- Identified smart water technology adoption barriers through interviews with water utility control room operators and green infrastructure developers in the metro Detroit area.
- Managed server infrastructure (AWS) and software back-end (Python, Bash, Unix) for a 250,000 km<sup>2</sup>, 160+ node IoT water sensor network.
- Supervised tasks, research agendas, and work output for 5 undergraduates, 2 master's students and 3 lab technicians.

# SENSOR, SIGNAL & INFORMATION PROCESSING CENTER, Tempe, Arizona, USA

May 2018 - Aug 2018

Research Intern, Arizona State University

• Worked with a team of 7 researchers to develop a low-power, renewable energy-charged illuminated buoy to reduce accidental wildlife catchment in fishing nets.

#### LORENZ QUANTUM COMPUTING RESEARCH GROUP, Urbana, Illinois, USA

May 2016 - Aug 2017

Undergraduate Research Assistant, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

• Prototyped components for table-top experiments with the goal of developing an optical quantum memory device.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### UNIVERSITY OF MICHIGAN, Ann Arbor, Michigan, USA

Aug 2019 - May 2024

PhD Intelligent Systems, Water / Civil Engineering

MSE Electrical Engineering, Signal & Image Processing and Machine Learning

MSE Civil Engineering, Intelligent Systems

## UNIVERSITY OF ILLINOIS, Urbana-Champaign, Illinois, USA

Aug 2015 - May 2019

BS Engineering Physics, Minors: Electrical Engineering, Informatics (Data Science), Geography

#### **SKILLS**

Programming Proficient: Python, Lack Shell/Bash Familiar: Javascript, HTML/CSS, MATLAB, Julia, Java Libraries/Frameworks Proficient: Numpy, Scikit-Learn, Pandas, Flask, PySWMM Familiar: React Tools/Platforms Proficient: Unix/Linux, Git, AWS, Adobe Creative Cloud, Microsoft Office Familiar: ArcGIS, Docker Languages English (Business Professional), Mandarin (Conversational - B1 / HSK 4)

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

- Measuring city-scale green infrastructure drawdown dynamics using internet-connected sensors in Detroit (October 2023), Environmental Science: Water Research & Technology, DOI: 10.1039/D3EW00098B
- Machine Learning-Assisted, Process-Based Quality Control for Detecting Compromised Environmental Sensors (August 2023), Environmental Science and Technology, DOI: 10.1021/acs.est.3c00360
- Climate Resiliency Through Data: Managing Stormwater Sewers in Detroit (April 2022), CHI Conference on Human Factors in Computing Systems Extended Abstracts, DOI: 10.1145/3491101.3516804